SOPHIE GOLOMB

Phone: (609) 439-3236 | Email: sgolomb1190@gmail.com | Brooklyn, NY

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophiegolomb | Portfolio: www.sophiegolomb.com

Creative professional passionate about developing socially impactful products and services. Strengths in visual design, UX ideation, teamwork, project management, and bringing ideas to fruition. My fine arts background coupled with professional experience as a graphic designer, communications specialist, and program manager, makes me a valuable addition to any team.

SKILLS

DESIGN: Graphic design, UX ideation and workflows, interaction and UI design, wireframing, and lo-

and hi-fi prototyping

USER RESEARCH: Interviews and surveys, usability testing, and qualitative analysis

TECHNICAL: Basic HTML, CSS, and JQuery

TOOLS: Figma, Adobe Xd, Illustrator, and Photoshop

PROJECTS

AN APP FOR THE "GIFT ECONOMY" | www.sophiegolomb.com/portfolio/green-elephant

This project was to create a way for users to easily and more conveniently exchange unwanted items and reduce their environmental impact.

- SKILLS: User Research (Interviews and Surveys), Competitor and Feature Analysis, User Persona Creation, User Flow and Storyboarding, Interaction Design, Paper and Lo-fi Wireframing, Prototyping, Guerilla User Testing, Branding
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: Figma, Adobe Illustrator

RESPONSIVE REDESIGN OF THE USDA WEBSITE | www.sophiegolomb.com/portfolio/usda

This project aimed to examine the existing website for the United States Department of Agriculture and create a cleaner and more approachable user interface and streamlined information architecture.

- **SKILLS:** User Interface Analysis (Redlining), User Path Creation, Usability Testing and Analysis, Card Sorting, Site Map Creation, Prototyping, User Interface Design, and Branding.
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: Invision. Adobe Xd and Illustrator

HUDSON RIVER CLEARWATER WEBSITE REDESIGN www.sophiegolomb.com/portfolio/clearwater

This project was a website redesign for the Hudson River Clearwater, a 50-year-old nonprofit dedicated to cleaning up the Hudson River and advocating for environmental protection. The redesign focused on giving the organization a more modern interface.

- **SKILLS:** Heuristic Evaluation, User Persona Creation, Usability Testing and Analysis, Card Sorting, Site Map Creation, Prototyping, User Interface Design, and Branding.
- TECHNOLOGIES USED: Figma, Invision

WORK EXPERIENCE

New York University, Senior Manager, Office of Sustainability

August 2015 - Present

- Strategize and apply design-thinking methodologies to communications, events, and programs
- Design internal presentations, infographics, reports, and event posters
- Draft and distribute a monthly newsletter to 6,000+ subscribers
- Manage website copy and layout to enhance user experience

Teen Advocates for Sustainability Corps (TASC), Founder & Director

September 2016-August 2020

- Conceived and executed every aspect of a three-day, environmental advocacy, youth conference for 100 NYC high school students
- Designed the logo and website for program promotion

College and Community Fellowship, Freelance Graphic Designer

May 2017 - April 2018

- Developed design concept and collateral for CCF's Harlem Renaissance themed gala and 2018
 Annual Report, disseminated to 200 attendees
- Helped inform the organization's development of a brand identity

Spicy Witch Productions, Freelance Graphic Designer

April 2015-May 2019

• Designed brochures and print postcards for five seasons

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Jewish Federations of North America, Administrative Aide

September 2014-August 2015

Religious Action Center for Reform Judaism, Legislative Assistant

August 2013-August 2014

EDUCATION

Certificate in UX/UI Design

Columbia Engineering June 2022

Master of Arts in Environmental Conservation Education

New York University May 2018

Bachelor of Arts in Studio Art and Anthropology

Magna Cum Laude; High Honors

Brandeis University May 2013